40歳という大人にとっては
２年というのは
To a forty-year-old adult, two years
might not make much of a difference.
さほどの意味を持たない
歳月かもしれない
At most, their hair might turn a little grayer, their body might lose a bit of vigor,
せいぜい ちょっぴり髪の毛が
白くなり 体に締まりがなくなり
ほんの少し 息切れがしやすくなる
and they might lose their breath more easily.
それが２年という月日の
平均的な効果だろう
That’s what happens to most in two years time.
だが 12歳の少年少女にとって
２年というのは
But for children twelve years of age,
two years is more than enough to bring about drastic changes, regardless of their era.
いつの時代も
劇的な変化をもたらすのに
十分な時間である
早季～っ！
Saki!
Geez, I told you to wait for me.
もう 待っててって言ったのに
ごめん ごめん
教室にいなかったから
Sorry, sorry.
You weren’t in the classroom, so
I figured you might’ve gone ahead.
先に行っちゃったかなと思って
Geez…
んっ も～っ…
ごめんてば
I said I’m sorry.
ちゃんと見たの？
Did you take a good look?
見たよ～
I did.
あらあら 覚と瞬も
相変わらず仲のいいこと
Look at that.
Satoru and Shun are as happy together as ever.
Hey.
よっ
やあ
Hi.
早季？
Saki.
Hmm? What is it?
え？ 何 どうしたの？
何でもないわ
Nothing.
We had all turned fourteen.
皆 14歳になっていた
Episode Eight
Omen
Saki, check this out.
早季 ほら どうよ
ちょっと ゆがんでるんじゃない？
Isn’t it a bit distorted?
What? Are you kidding me?
はあ～？ 何 言ってんだよ
完璧な平面だろ
It’s perfectly flat!
The middle of my face isn’t that sunken-in!
私の顔
こんなに しゃくれてないわ
何だよ ゆがんでんのは
お前の心の方だろ？
What? Isn’t it your heart that’s distorted here?!
ウフフッ…
えいっ！
…って～ てめ～！
Ouch! You little—
Sorry, I didn’t see you there.
あ～ら ごめん 気がつかなかった
どうだい？ ヒナが
形成される感触はあるかい？
Well? Can you feel the chick in its egg, growing and taking shape?
いえ まだなんとなくって感じです
No, all I have so far is this vague feeling.
かなり高度な課題だからね
だが 青沼君なら大丈夫だろう
It’s a challenging task, to be sure.
But if anybody can do it, it’s you, Aonuma-kun.
早く かわいいヒヨコを
見せてほしいなあ
Please let me see that adorable little chick soon.
Shun!
瞬…
How is it? Going well?
どう うまくいってる？
ばっちり ばっちり
Piece of cake.
凄いね
何 言ってんだよ
You’re really good.
Come on.
瞬の課題に比べたら全然
２時間で羽化させるんだろ～？
It’s nothing compared to your task.
You have to hatch it in two hours, right?
そんなことないよ
You’re exaggerating.
Everyone expects great things from you, man.
瞬への期待度は半端ないからな～
いっつ…
Want to go to the infirmary?
保健室 行く？
I’m okay.
大丈夫 たいしたことないから
It’s just a little cut.
ちょっと見せて どれどれ
Let me see.
Hmm…
う～ん… 血は平気かもね～
The bleeding shouldn’t be too bad.
すばる～！
Subaru!
って ことは…？
This must mean…
Subaru!
すばる～！
やっぱり！
There he is!
Wait, Shun!
待ってよ 瞬！
うわっ
Got you!
捕まえた！ アハハハ…
離せよ
Let go.
イヤだって言ったら？
And if I said no?
やったな
Now you’ve done it.
だからさ… あっ…
Like I said—
真理亜！ 真理亜！
うん？
Maria! Maria!
ハア ハア…
真理亜～っ
Maria!
あらあら どうしたの？
Oh my, what’s wrong?
You’re just like a child right now.
まるで子供みたい
今日の早季ったら
散歩に行きたいの
Take a walk with me.
散歩？
A walk?
お願い
Please!
All right.
いいわよ
We’re going to take a walk.
じゃあ 私たち 散歩してくるから
ちょっと休憩してて
Let’s continue later.
ありがとう
上手に描いてくれて うれしいわ
Thanks.
I really appreciate the beautiful portrait.
That’s why they went looking for green stones.
それで緑色の石を
探しにいったんだって
くぬぎ林の渓流には
結構あるみたいよ
I think there’s plenty near the mountain stream that runs through the little oak forest.
So, what happened?
ねえ 何があったの？
ねえってば？
Come on, tell me.
答えなきゃ何もしてあげない
I won’t do anything unless you answer me.
早季も 早く！
Come on in!
ウフフ…
うふふ… あはは…！
あっ… 真理亜… 真理亜…
Maria…
人間の社会もまた
The scientists considered it their immediate duty
ボノボ型の愛の社会に
to create a society of love similar to that of bonobos.
作り替えることが急務でした
ね あれ
Hey, look.
きっと 覚がマネしたのよ
I bet Satoru copied it.
いつの間にか あの子ったら
瞬のマネばかりね
Lately he’s been trying so much to be like Shun.
そうだね… どうでもいいけど…
Yeah…
It’s none of my business, though.
ねえ 楽しい？
え…
Hey… is it fun?
誰ともつきあわずにさ
真理亜だけ そんな追いかけて
Being alone and chasing after Maria.
楽しいって聞いてるの
あっ あ…
Is it really that fun?
守も早く 恋人 作れば？
Why don’t you find someone too?
ねぇ 私たちも
何か おそろいにしない？
Hey, we should match, too.
え？ うん いいけど…
Fine with me…
ん～ やっぱり やめ やめ
Actually, let’s not.
なんか マネしてるみたいで
バカらしいもんね
We’ll look dumb trying to copy them.
Hey! Wait, Saki!
あっ ねえ 待ってよ 早季
何やってんだろう 私たち…
What on Earth are we doing?
Yeah, I’ll be fine.
うん 大丈夫 行ってきま～す
See you later!
行ってらっしゃい
Bye!
Hey, cheer up.
なあ 機嫌直してくれよ
どうしたんだよ 瞬？
What’s wrong, Shun?
Nothing. I just need some time alone.
なんでもないよ
ちょっと １人にしてくれ
It was my fault.
俺が悪かったよ
Please!
頼むから…
Fault? What was?
悪かった？ 何が？
それは…
I…
Satoru, can we stop acting like we’re lovers now?
覚 恋愛ごっこは
もういいだろう？
僕は 君のお人形さんになるのに
いいかげん飽き飽きしたんだ
I’m fed up with being your little doll.
ああ… 分かった これからは…
I get it. I’ll change.
No, you don’t get it.
分かってないね こんなふうに
四六時中つきまとわれても
Being together around the clock is suffocating.
暑苦しいだけなんだよ
僕は１人になりたいんだ
I want to be alone.
だから 今日からは
お互い別行動にしよう
Let’s go our separate ways.
じゃあな
See you.
どうして？
Why…?
あっ 覚 見っけた エヘ…
There y’are, Satoru.
怜…
Rei…
ウフ…
あの様子だと 覚がふったのかな？
Does this mean Satoru dumped him?
でも 瞬に夢中だったのに…
やっぱり 瞬かな？
But he was all over Shun…
Was it Shun, then?
さあ…
Who knows?
なんだか バラバラになってくね…
We’re drifting apart.
私と早季の間は永遠よね？
Saki and I will be together forever, right?
Yeah.
あっ！ 見て
ああ？ あれ あれ！ あれ
Hey, look!
なに なに？
こっ これは 鏑木様
ようこそいらっしゃいました
H-Heavens, Kaburagi-sama!
Welcome to our class!
Is this a bad time?
邪魔かな？
とっ とんでもございません
N-Not at all!
ああ 鏑木様に
じきじきに来ていただけるとは
I cannot imagine an honor greater than having you visit my class.
これ以上に光栄なことは
ございません
ああ…
何か お気にかかることでも？
Is there anything in particular on your mind?
いや ない たまには
今後を担う子供たちの学びを…
No, there isn’t.
I simply thought I’d check in on what our next generation is learning.
ねえねえ 鏑木肆星が
何で ここに？
Hey, what’s Kaburagi Shisei doing here?
On the contrary, I’d like to see a normal class.
I heard he could use his Cantus to
split the Earth in half if he focused.
あの人 本気で集中したら
地球を真っ二つにするくらいの
Very well. This way, please.
呪力があるんだって 知ってた？
Did you know that?
No, but it wouldn’t surprise me if he could. He is the most powerful Cantus user.
ううん
でも 最強の呪力の持ち主だから
それぐらい できても
不思議はないけど…
ああ もう！ 何でもいいわ
Anyway, this is a great chance to draw some praise!
とにかく
認められるチャンスだもの
Not very exciting, huh?
やっぱり地味すぎるのよね
What are you imagining to create it?
どのようなイメージで
作っているんだい？
Sir! I am imagining a perfectly flat lacquered board!
あっ はい！ あの…
ゆがみの全くない 漆塗りの板を
イメージしています！
ふん… 難しい課題の１つだが
なかなかの出来だね
It’s a difficult exercise,
but you’re doing quite well.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
その調子で励むように
Keep up the good work.
Yessir!
はい！
さっすが 覚！
Good job, Satoru!
Everyone was waiting for a historic encounter.
誰もが 歴史的な出会いを期待した
瞬は いずれは鏑木肆星氏の
Shun was a genius expected to eventually inherit Kaburagi Shisei’s mantle.
衣鉢を継ぐと目されている
生徒である
He could receive firsthand advice from the great master for the first time.
ここで 初めて じかに指導を
受けることになるのだろうと
ああっ あの！
お待ちください
どうされたのですか？
Please, wait!
What is wrong?
Did something offend you?
何か失礼でも
ございましたでしょうか？
えっ 本当ですか？
Really?!
いっ いえ
疑うなんて めっそうもない…
No, not at all!
I would never doubt your judgment.
どうなってるの？
What’s going on?
Yes… Yes…
なあ 何が起きたのかな？
What happened?
分かんない 分かんないけど…
I don’t know. I don’t know, but…
ええと 都合により
今日の実技の時間は
Due to unforeseen circumstances, we’ll end today’s practice here.
中止になりました
え～！
Please clean up your workspaces and return to your classrooms.
各自 片づけて
教室に戻ってください
ねえ 覚 行こうよ ねえってば
Hey, Satoru, let’s go! Come on!
先に行ってくれよ 後から行くから
Go on ahead.
I’ll catch up.
もう… ちぇっ
Geez!
はいはい
君たちも 早く片づけなさい
Come on! Clean up!
Let’s go, Shun.
瞬 行かないの？
Right.
Hey, that…
ねえ それ…
Yeah…
Come on, go!
さあさあ
君たち 早く行きなさい！
後は先生が片づけておくから
I’ll clean up the rest!
瞬のことだから
I was surprised Shun didn’t stop the egg in midair when it fell.
卵を空中でピッと止めると
思ったんだけどなあ
Shun, are you okay?
瞬 大丈夫なのか？
ああ 大したことない
Yeah, I’m fine.
ちょっと疲れただけだから
I’m just a little tired.
もう 早退すれば？
Want to go home early?
Nah, I’m fine.
いや 本当に平気
なんか…
何？
This…
What?
なんか 懐かしい感じ
最近 ５人揃ってなかったから
This feels so nostalgic!
We’ve been kind of apart recently.
アッハハ… ハハハ…
瞬！
Shun!
どうしたの？
Is something wrong?
早季…
Saki…
来るな！
Don’t come closer!
あっ… どうして？
Why?
ごめん でも１人になりたいんだ
Sorry… but I want to be alone.
１人に？
ああ
Alone?
Yeah.
Is that why you broke up with Satoru?
だから 覚とも別れたの？
まあ そうかな…
I guess…
友達を捨ててまで
１人になりたいの？
Do you want to be alone so badly that you’d abandon your friends?
それは 説明しても
早季には分からないよ
Even if I explained, I don’t think you’d understand.
I don’t think we’ll be able to meet for a while.
しばらく 会えなくなると思う
えっ どういうこと？
How come?
当分 学校へは行けない
I’ll be out of school for a while.
僕は療養しなきゃならないんだ
I have to get special treatment.
病気なの？
Are you sick?
うん 病気っていうか…
どう言えば分かるかな
Sick… well…
I don’t know how to explain it.
体の病気ではないんだ
It’s not my body that’s sick.
じゃあ 僕はもう行かなきゃ
Anyway, I have to go.
待って！
お見舞いに行ってもいい？
Wait!
Can I come visit you?
I don’t think so.
どうかな？
えっ？
僕は もう家には いられないし
I can’t stay at home anymore, either.
あっ… どこに行くの？
Where are you going, then?
療養のための
小さなバンガローだよ
To a small bungalow, for rehabilitation.
Where is it?
それ どこにあるの？
ごめん 場所は
言ってはいけないことになってる
Sorry. I can’t tell you that.
瞬 本当に
１人ぼっちになっちゃったの？
Shun, will you really be all alone?
What about Subaru?
すばるは どうしたの？
家にいるよ 散歩したくなったから
He’s at home.
I just wanted to take a walk, so I snuck out alone.
１人で こっそり
抜け出してきたんだ
私 どうすれば瞬の力になれるの？
Is there any way I can help you?
Shun, I’ve always lo—
瞬 私 ずっと瞬のことが…
Saki, I should tell you at least this much.
早季 迷ったんだけどね
やっぱり このことだけは
言っておいた方がいいと思う
Remember the summer camp two years ago?
２年前の夏季キャンプ 覚えてる？
Yeah.
Our Cantus was sealed by Rijin,
僕らは離塵師に
呪力を凍結されたけど
でも それは
うまく隠し通せたと思ってた
but we thought that we managed to hide that.
Right.
We didn’t.
でも そうじゃなかったんだ
｢そうじゃない｣って？
What?
多分 全部バレてたんだ
どういう意図かは分からないけど
I’d say they knew it all along.
I don’t know why, but I think they
simply decided to delay punishing us.
単に処分を
保留にされてただけなんだよ
言ってる意味
よく分かんないんだけど
I’m not sure where this is going.
僕らは ずっと監視されていたんだ
We’ve probably been under constant surveillance.
今さら こんな警告をしても
意味ないかもしれない
I don’t think I really have to warn you by now,
でも 早季 猫には気をつけて
but, Saki, watch out for the cats.
Cats? You mean the Copycats?
猫？ ネコダマシのこと？
Here, take this.
そうだ これ あげるよ
あっ 何？ これ
What’s this?
猫よけのおまじない
僕が作ったんだ
A charm against the cats.
I made it.
すばるとおそろいなの？
Subaru has the same, doesn’t he?
アハ…
Please let the others know, too.
僕が言ったこと
みんなに伝えてほしいんだ
Silly dog. I told you not to follow me.
馬鹿だな あれほど
ついてくるなって言ったのに
Nakisou na aoringo kakaeteru mune no oku
泣きそうな青リンゴ  抱えてる胸の奥
In my chest, I carry a green apple that wets my eyes
Korogatte tsuyogatte
転がって  強がって
I fall over yet pretend to be strong
Kyuukutsu na sora niramu
窮屈な空睨む
I glower at the sky and it seems to suffocate me
Unmei ni juujun ni
運命に従順に
Do I look like I'd wait quietly
Jukusu no wo matsu mon ka
熟すのを待つもんか
For destiny to ripen it?
Sen no kaze
千の風
The winds
Agaite sakende
あがいて  叫んで
I struggle and scream
Fuke fuke
吹け吹け
Blow and blow
Watashi wa shabondama
わたしはしゃぼん玉
I'm a soap bubble
Soredemo shinjiteru
それでも信じてる
And still I have faith
Yokisenu arashi ni
予期せぬ  嵐に
In a sudden storm
Joushou shite kakou shite
上昇して  下降して
I rise and fall
Aragau shabondama
あらがうしゃぼん玉
I fight, soap bubble that I am
Soredemo ikiteku
それでも生きてく
And still I live on
Hajikeru shunkan niji hanate
弾ける瞬間  虹、放て
I make a rainbow when I burst
I can’t believe this…
信じられない 何 これ…
シッ！
What’s going on?!
遠藤先生が言ったのよ
Mr. Endou said…
｢あんなに優秀な子だったのに
残念だ｣って
“What a pity. He was such a talented boy.”
瞬は？ 瞬はどうなったの？
Shun? What happened to Shun?!